631 Huntleigh Dr. Lafayette, CA - 1601 Rice Blvd. Houston, TX

🛮 +1 (925)788-6276 | 💌 Inm7@rice.edu | 🛠 leomarek.github.io | 🖸 github.com/leomarek | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/leo-marek

Personal Profile

I am a student at Rice University studying computer science as well as electrical and computer engineering. I am passionate about software engineering, computational modeling, data science, embedded systems, and the intersection between hardware and software design. On the side, I love working on design projects and IOT devices. When I am not busy at school or working on projects I am passionate about the outdoors as I am an advanced downhill skier, collegiate sailor, experienced backpacker, and mountain biker.

Education

Rice University Houston, TX

BSECE, BACS

Sept 2022 - Present

- · Rice Electric Vehicle Subteam Lead: oversee the 20-person electrical team, design, build, and debug custom electronics for our entry to the shell eco-marathon
- IEEE Representative: plan IEEE events and corporate recruiting lunches, coordinate with conferences
- Rice CS Club: HackRice, Coursework Support
- Rice Data Science: Data Science Bootcamp, Rice Datathon
- · Courses: Computational Thinking, Discrete Math, Computer Engineering, Honors Linear Algebra, Multivariable Calculus

Athenian School Danville, CA

High School

Aug 2018 - May 2022

- · 40-person FIRST Robotics team Captain, 1200+ hours
- Investment Club, Varsity Sailing (captain), Entrepreneurship, Math Club founding member, Ultimate Frisbee
- Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms

Experience

Rice Computer Science Department

Houston, TX

Teaching Assistant

Jul 2023 - Present

- Assist computational thinking instruction for first-year CS students
- · Teach Python, Graphs, Matrix Operations, Linear Regression, Model Fitting, Error Correction, and Markov Chains

Oshman Engineering Design Kitchen

Houston, TX

Laboratory Assistant

Encinal Yacht Club

Jul 2023 - Present

• Instruct machine and tool usage to students in and out of classes · Use lab tools and equipment including 3d printers, laser cutters, waterjet cutter, plasma cutter, electrical instrumentation, and cnc machines

Alameda, CA May 2021 - Present

Sailing Instructor • Instructed new sailors aged 8-68, created lesson plans, and led students in exercises on the water

Alloy Technologies

San Francisco, CA

Intern Mar 2020 - Apr 2020

· Produced marketing content and helped coordinate events to demonstrate to clients the benefits of smart supply chain analytics

Expertise

Skills Software Development, Data Engineering, Robotics, Machine Learning, Electronics, Object-Oriented Programming

Technologies Java, Python, Robotics, C, Autodesk EAGLE, R, Microcontrollers, Git, CAN bus, Excel, Matlab, HTML, CSS Certifications US Sailing Small Boat Instructor, International Offshore Safety at Sea, Red Cross First Aid/CPR/AED

Projects ____

School and Personal Projects

Check out all my projects on leomarek.github.io

Languages_

English Native proficiency Spanish Professional proficiency

JUNE 30, 2023